Another way to delete all the information within
a table is to run a TRUNCATE TABLE statement
with the table name. With DELETE, you can specify
criteria to use for what is deleted from a table.
With TRUNCATE TABLE, the table is emptied,
as there are no criteria to be specified.
Also, note that a table with a one-to-many
relationship with another table will, by default,
have the records from the many table deleted
if any records from the one table are deleted.
To illustrate this, I am going to show some
records from the Sales.SalesOrderHeader table.
This table has a one-to-many relationship
with the Sales.SalesOrderDetail table.
If I were to delete specific records from this
table, any records with the same sales order
numbers in the SalesOrderDetail
table would be deleted as well.
For this reason, it is so important to be
careful with any deletes from any tables.